You Don't Know The ½ Of It!
The Lion King 1½ is a family, animation, comedy
film directed by Bradley Raymond.
Timon the meerkat and Pumbaa the warthog are best pals and
the unsung heroes of the African savanna.
This prequel to the smash Disney animated adventure takes you
back -- way back -- before Simba's adventure began.
You'll find out all about Timon and Pumbaa and tag along as they search for
the perfect home and attempt to raise a rambunctious lion cub.
Timon (voice), played by Nathan Lane.
Pumbaa (voice), played by Ernie Sabella.
Mom (voice), played by Julie Kavner.
Uncle Max (voice), played by Jerry Stiller.
Simba (voice), played by Matthew Broderick.
Rafiki (voice), played by Robert Guillaume.
The Lion King 1½ (known internationally as The Lion King 3: Hakuna Matata) is a 2004 American animated direct-to-video
musical comedy film directed by Bradley Raymond, produced by Disneytoon Studios and released on February 10, 2004.
The third and final installment in the Lion King trilogy, the film is both a prequel and sidequel
to The Lion King (1994), focusing on the supporting characters Timon and Pumbaa.
A majority of the voice cast from the first film returns to reprise their roles, including
Nathan Lane and Ernie Sabella as the voices of Timon and Pumbaa, respectively.
The film's structure is inspired by Tom Stoppard's Rosencrantz and Guildenstern Are Dead, a
tragicomedy that tells the story of Hamlet from the point of view of two minor characters.
The Lion King 1½ received generally positive reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of pig, africa, lion, cartoon, sequel.
The tone is lighthearted.